So how do neural networks fit into reinforcement learning?
如何在强化学习中使用神经网络
Well, remember how neural networks are touted as universal function approximators?
还记得我们将神经网络介绍为通用函数逼近器这部分内容吗？
What if we use neural networks to represent our value functions?
如果我们使用神经网络表示值函数呢？
Would that work? Let's take a closer look.
可行吗？我们来仔细研究下
A state value function maps any state as to a real number
状态值函数将任何状态 s 映射到实数
which indicates how valuable that state is according to the current policy pi.
表示根据当前策略 π 该状态的重要性
If we used a neural network to approximate this function,
如果我们使用神经网络估算该函数
then the input would need to be fed in as a vector.
则输入需要以向量的形式提供进来
Now we already know how to do this using a feature transformation x.
现在我们已经知道如何使用特征转换 x 执行这一步
Now the input can progress through the network.
现在输入可以经过神经网络
And if it is designed to output a single real number,
如果它旨在输出一个实数
that is our value,
即网络
as estimated by the network.
估算的值
Great! This seems to fall in place with
很棒！这与利用形成参数向量 W 的
the general idea of approximating a value function with the weights of
神经网络权重估算值函数
the neural network forming the parameter vector W.
这一基本概念相符
The question is how do we learn these parameters.
问题是如何学习这些参数
If we have a reference or a target we're trying to reach, for example,
如果我们有一个参考或想要实现的目标
V pi provided by some oracle we can use
例如某个预言者提供的 vπ 我们可以将估算值和目标值
the squared difference between the estimated and target value as our error or loss.
之间的平方差当做误差或损失
Then we can back propagate it through the network
然后我们可以沿着神经网络
adjusting weights along the way to minimize loss.
反向传播并调整权重 以便最小化损失
One popular method for adjusting weights is gradient descent,
调整权重的一个热门方法是梯度下降
where we iteratively change weights a small step away from the direction of error.
我们朝着误差的反方向以迭代方式小步地更改权重
In order to apply gradient descent,
为了应用梯度下降
we need to know the derivative of the value function
我们需要知道网络表示的
represented by the network with respect to its weights.
相对于权重的值函数
Now this can become very complex,
这一步可能会非常复杂
especially for networks with deep architectures.
尤其是具有深度架构的网络
But we have pretty efficient algorithms implemented in libraries like TensorFlow,
但是我们在 TensorFlow Theano 和 MXNet 等库中
Theano, and MXNet to train neural nets for us.
实现了非常高效的算法 可以帮助我们训练神经网络
All we need is a way to figure out
我们只需用于计算损失的方法
the loss and that's where our knowledge of reinforcement learning comes in.
这时候强化学习知识就派上用场了
At this point, let's also consider the action value function Q.
此刻 我们再考虑下动作值函数 Q
The update rule looks very similar to what we had for
更新规则看起来和状态值函数 V 的非常相似
the state value function V. But we have the same problem here.
但是这里具有相同的问题
For most practical problems,
对于大多数实际问题
there is no oracle to tell us what the correct value function V pi or Q pi should be.
没有预言家能告诉我们正确的值函数 vπ 或 qπ 应该是多少
We need to use a more realistic target.
我们需要使用更加现实的目标
One that is based on our interactions with the environment.
这个目标基于我们与环境的互动
This is where reinforcement learning fundamentally differs from supervised learning.
这正是强化学习与监督学习的根本区别
Next we'll look at some strategies we can apply to find
接下来我们将了解如何查找合适的目标
suitable targets to use in place of the true value functions in these equations.
以便替换这些方程中的真正值函数所采用的策略